<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Python Scouts - Tutoriales</title><link href="https://pythonscouts.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://pythonscouts.github.io/feeds/tutoriales.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://pythonscouts.github.io/</id><updated>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>El Estilo de Codificación de Python Sugún PEP 8</title><link href="https://pythonscouts.github.io/python-coding-style-pep8.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leodanis Pozo Ramos</name></author><id>tag:pythonscouts.github.io,2023-03-22:/python-coding-style-pep8.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this article, you'll learn the basics of Python's coding style rules. These rules are defined in PEP 8.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Python is a popular and easy-to-learn programming language that has gained a lot of traction over the years. However, as with any programming language, it's important to write clean, readable, and maintainable code. This is where coding style comes in. A consistent and well-defined coding style can make code easier to read and understand, which can save time and prevent bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;&lt;span class="toctitle"&gt;Tabla de contenido&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#why-coding-style-matters"&gt;Why Coding Style Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-pep-8-style-guide"&gt;The PEP 8 Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-coding-style-matters"&gt;Why Coding Style Matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding style is important for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readability: Code that is easy to read and understand is less prone to errors and easier to maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency: A consistent coding style throughout a project makes it easier for multiple developers to work together and ensures that the code is easy to read and maintain over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community: Following a widely accepted coding style makes it easier for others to read and understand your code and can make it easier to contribute to open source projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-pep-8-style-guide"&gt;The PEP 8 Style Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python community has established a widely accepted coding style guide called PEP 8 (Python Enhancement Proposal 8). The PEP 8 style guide provides a set of guidelines for writing Python code that is easy to read and understand. Here are some key points from the PEP 8 style guide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use 4 spaces for indentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use lowercase letters for variable names and function names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use CamelCase for class names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put a space before and after operators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put a space after commas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put a space after colons in function definitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put a space before and after a comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use docstrings to document code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use one import per line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use whitespace to separate logical blocks of code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit line length to 79 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use single quotes for string literals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use underscores to separate words in variable names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid using a single uppercase letter as a variable name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use meaningful names for variables, functions, and classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the PEP 8 style guide covers many aspects of coding style, here are 15 of the most important rules to follow. These rules will help make your code more readable and consistent with the PEP 8 style guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the PEP 8 style guide and other established coding styles can help you write cleaner, more maintainable code. By following a consistent coding style, you can make your code easier to read and understand, which can save time and prevent bugs. Keep these rules in mind when writing Python code to ensure that your code is clean, readable, and maintainable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tutoriales"></category><category term="core-python"></category><category term="basics"></category></entry><entry><title>Qué es Python y Cuáles Son sus Características Fundamentales</title><link href="https://pythonscouts.github.io/python-features.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leodanis Pozo Ramos</name></author><id>tag:pythonscouts.github.io,2023-03-22:/python-features.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this article, you'll learn about the main features of the Python programming language.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By the end of this article, you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the history of Python and how it was created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the main features of Python and how they make it stand out among other programming languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appreciate the simplicity and ease of use of Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the importance of the large standard library in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the advantages of dynamic typing in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;&lt;span class="toctitle"&gt;Tabla de contenido&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-python"&gt;What is Python?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#short-history-of-python"&gt;Short History of Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#hight-level-features-of-python"&gt;Hight Level Features of Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-python"&gt;What is Python?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a high-level, interpreted programming language that is widely used in various industries. In this article, we will discuss the main features of Python and what makes it stand out among other programming languages. By the end of this article, you will be able to understand the key features of Python and why it is so popular among developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="short-history-of-python"&gt;Short History of Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python was created in the late 1980s by Guido van Rossum, a Dutch programmer. It was first released in 1991 and since then, it has been continuously evolving. The language is named after the Monty Python comedy group, as Guido van Rossum was a big fan of their shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hight-level-features-of-python"&gt;Hight Level Features of Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is known for its simplicity and ease of use. It has a clean and simple syntax, which makes it easy to learn and read. Some of the main features of Python are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpreted Language: Python is an interpreted language, which means that the code is executed line by line. This makes it easy to test and debug code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object-Oriented: Python is an object-oriented language, which means that it supports the concept of classes and objects. This makes it easy to organize code and reuse code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross-Platform: Python can run on multiple platforms, including Windows, Linux, and macOS. This makes it a versatile language that can be used for various applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large Standard Library: Python comes with a large standard library, which makes it easy to perform various tasks such as file handling, networking, and web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic Typing: Python is a dynamically typed language, which means that the type of a variable is determined at runtime. This makes it easy to write code and prototype applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a powerful programming language that is widely used in various industries. Its simplicity, ease of use, and versatility make it a popular choice among developers. By learning Python, you will be able to build various applications and perform various tasks. So, if you're interested in learning a programming language, Python is definitely worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tutoriales"></category><category term="core-python"></category><category term="basics"></category></entry><entry><title>El Zen de Python Según PEP 20</title><link href="https://pythonscouts.github.io/python-zen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Leodanis Pozo Ramos</name></author><id>tag:pythonscouts.github.io,2023-03-22:/python-zen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this article, you'll learn about the Zen of Python, a set of 20 general principles that you should apply in your day-to-day coding in Python.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Zen of Python is a collection of guiding principles for writing computer programs in the Python language. These principles were first introduced by Tim Peters, a well-known Python developer, in a Python mailing list post in 1999. Since then, the Zen of Python has become a central part of the Python community and is often referenced in discussions and talks about Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this article, you will have learned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What the Zen of Python is and why it is important in the Python community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 19 Zen Principles and what they mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to apply the Zen Principles in your own code to make it more readable and maintainable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="toc"&gt;&lt;span class="toctitle"&gt;Tabla de contenido&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-zen-of-python"&gt;What is the Zen of Python?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-zen-principles"&gt;The Zen Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-zen-of-python"&gt;What is the Zen of Python?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zen of Python is a set of 19 aphorisms that aim to guide developers in writing better, more readable, and more maintainable code. These aphorisms, which are also known as the "Zen Principles", are built around the idea that code should be simple, clear, and easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-zen-principles"&gt;The Zen Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zen of Python includes 19 principles that cover various aspects of programming, such as code readability, simplicity, and the importance of testing. Here are a few examples of the Zen Principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beautiful is better than ugly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple is better than complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readability counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Errors should never pass silently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be one-- and preferably only one --obvious way to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zen of Python provides a set of guiding principles that can help developers write better, more readable, and more maintainable code. By following these principles, you can improve the quality of your code and make it easier for others to understand and work with. So next time you're writing Python code, remember the Zen of Python and strive to make your code beautiful, simple, and readable!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tutoriales"></category><category term="core-python"></category><category term="basics"></category></entry></feed>